Rupak Lazarus

□ +91 9913214027 | ☑ rupak.lazarus@research.iiit.ac.in | □ rupakl | □ rupak-lazarus



Objective and Research Statement

To be part of a progressive organization that gives scope to enhance my knowledge, skills and to reach the pinnacle in the Computer Vision and Deep Learning field with sheer determination, dedication and hard work. My research lies at the intersection of Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing and Knowledge representation. My current research focus is on developing methods to understand chart images in academic documents.

Education _

International Institute of Information Technology Hyderabad

Hyderabad, India

Aug 2020 - Aug 2022 (Expected)

MS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING BY RESEARCH

- CGPA: 8.0/10.0
- $\bullet \ \ {\it Courses: Computer Vision, Statistical Methods in AI, Mobile Robotics, Optimization Methods.}\\$

Kadi Sarva Vishwavidyalaya

Gandhinagar, India

July 2013 - July 2017

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

- CGPA: 8.23/10.0
- Courses: Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Discrete mathematics.

Holy Cross School Tadong, India

ALL INDIA SENIOR SECONDARY CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION

• Percentage: 89.8%

May 2013

Experience ____

AlMonk Labs Private Limited

Bengaluru, India

SENIOR MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

May 2019 - Aug 2020

Final version will not have this

AlMonk Labs Private Limited

Bengaluru, India

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

July 2017 - May 2019

- Developed object detection training pipeline for **Video Analytics System** for different use cases like weapon detection, bike rider helmet detection, accident detection.
- Training neural networks for different tasks like Font discrimination, Face Detection and Recognition, Text Detection and Recognition, Image Classification, etc.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Writing training and inference code of research papers like } \textbf{Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks} \ \text{and replicating the results}.$
- Creating synthetic datasets using OpenCV and deep learning models for pre-training neural networks.
- Writing API's and designing distributed architecture for scalable deployment of deep learning models to accept inference request of images and videos in real time.

Skills _____

Programming Languages C++, Python, HTML, Javascript **Operating Systems** Linux, Windows, Mac OS

Deep Learning Frameworks PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras Tools and Libraries Git, Docker, OpenCV, Numpy, Flask, ŁTĘX

Achievements _____

2018	2nd place , Deep Learning 3 Challenge on HackerEarth	Beng
2017	Elet rank (ton 906) Cdiscount's Imago classification Challenge on Kaggle	Rong

51st rank (top 9%), Cdiscount's Image classification Challenge on Kaggle
4th place, Rakuten Deep Learning Challenge
Bengaluru, India
Bengaluru, India